<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Always True, Always False :: Maximum Mathematics</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/the-book-of-foundational-mathematics/logic/always-true-always-false/index.html</link>
    <description>Now that we have a fairly organized way of analyzing the truth value of compound propositions, we’ll start to see some interesting phenomena crop up from time-to-time. We’ll do this by looking at all possible values a proposition can take, which is precisely what truth tables allow us to do.&#xA;Tautologies Example 1.3.1 Let&#39;s examine the proposition $p \rightarrow (p \lor q)$. We&#39;ll start with a blank truth table. We start by filling out the column for $p \lor q$: Now that we have the truth values for propositions $p$ and $p \lor q$, it is easy to calculate the truth values for $p \rightarrow (p \lor q)$: Now we remove the extraneous column for $p \lor q$ to get the final truth table: All of the values in the final column are $1$! This means that, no matter what truth values $p$ and $q$ have, the expression $p \rightarrow (p \lor q)$ is always $\text{true}$. $$~$$ Translating the proposition $p \rightarrow (p \lor q)$ into English yields something like this: $$\text{If p, then p or q.}$$ Of course if we start with proposition $p$, then we must also have $p \lor q$ as well because $p$ is included in the conclusion. For example, suppose we had that \[ \begin{align*} p &amp;: \text{Phil opens up a new savings account.} \\ q &amp;: \text{Phil earns 4% interest every year, compounded monthly.} \end{align*} \] Then the proposition $p \rightarrow (p \lor q)$ can be translated as follows: \[ \begin{align*} &amp;\text{If Phil opens up a new savings account, then} \\ &amp;\text{either Phil opens up a new savings account, or } \\ &amp;\text{he will earn 4% interest every year compounded monthly, } \\ &amp;\text{or both.} \end{align*} \] $$~$$ Of course if Phil opens a new savings account, then he will either open up a new savings account (which he just supposedly did), or he will earn 4% interest compounded monthly, or both. There is a special name for propositions that are always true, no matter what truth values are held by its constituent parts.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/the-book-of-foundational-mathematics/logic/always-true-always-false/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>