<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Functions :: Maximum Mathematics</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/the-book-of-foundational-mathematics/functions/index.html</link>
    <description>In the previous chapter, we studied a way to relate elements of one set to another set. However, we didn’t place any restrictions on those relations. Usually, we want to have some specific type of structure in the way we relate elements.&#xA;Throughout our normal schooling, we encounter many types of these structured relations. Specifically, the kinds of relations we studied were functions. In this chapter, we delve deeper into these special kind of relations, and study them in an abstract sense. That is to say, what we discuss here will be applicable to all functions, not just those more familiar functions that relate real numbers to other real numbers.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 02:51:54 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/the-book-of-foundational-mathematics/functions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Functions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-book-of-foundational-mathematics/functions/functions/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 21:39:58 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-book-of-foundational-mathematics/functions/functions/index.html</guid>
      <description>In this chapter’s introduction, we mentioned that a function is a specific kind of relation, which means there are additional requirements for a relation to be a function that extend beyond simply being a subset of some cross product $A \times B$. Before we give the definition, let’s look at some relations that behave differently from one another to get a more intuitive sense of what we’re looking for in a function.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special Functions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-book-of-foundational-mathematics/functions/special-functions/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 21:40:09 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-book-of-foundational-mathematics/functions/special-functions/index.html</guid>
      <description>We have defined functions basically as special types of relations. We can go further and recognize that some functions have special properties different than other functions. In this section, we examine three properties that tend to be useful when working on various problems all throughout mathematics.&#xA;Surjective Functions Example 6.2.1 Consider the sets $A = \{1, 2, 3, 4, 5\}$ and $B = \{\alpha, \beta, \gamma, \delta\}$. In Figure 6.2.1 below, we use an arrow diagram to define two functions $f_1$ and $f_2$ from $A$ to $B$. Figure 6.2.1</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Properties of Functions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-book-of-foundational-mathematics/functions/properties-of-functions/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 02:16:45 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-book-of-foundational-mathematics/functions/properties-of-functions/index.html</guid>
      <description>In the last section, we talked about certain kinds of functions that have properties not had by other functions. Surjective functions have properties not shared with injective functions, and vice-versa. In this section, we swing back to talking about properties that all functions have, though the last property we talk about is a bit more refined when the underlying function is injective.&#xA;Empty Inputs Produce Empty Outputs One classic analogy mathematicians use to talk about functions is that of a machine. Simply put, a machine is a device that takes in some input, operates on that input, and produces an output. Like machines, a function takes in an input, and based on how the function is defined, produces an output.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Equal Functions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-book-of-foundational-mathematics/functions/equal-functions/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 02:51:54 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-book-of-foundational-mathematics/functions/equal-functions/index.html</guid>
      <description>We’ve previously discussed when two sets are considered equal, and when two ordered pairs are equal. We then extended the idea of set equality to see when two Cartesian products were considered equal (because Cartesian products are simply sets of ordered pairs).&#xA;However, we have not yet discussed when two relations are equal. As we saw in Section 5.6 Characterizing Relations, the sets on which a relation is defined can drastically alter that relation’s properties. A relation $\mathcal{R}$ may be reflexive on $A^2$, but may not be reflexive on $B^2$ even though $\mathcal{R}$ is the same set in each case.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composite Functions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-book-of-foundational-mathematics/functions/composite-functions/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 21:40:20 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-book-of-foundational-mathematics/functions/composite-functions/index.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>