<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Relations :: Maximum Mathematics</title>
    <link>http://hiancemathbooks.com/relations/index.html</link>
    <description>Relations are used all throughout mathematics. Examples of relations abound in subjects such as algebra, trigonometry, calculus, as well as computer science, physics, chemistry, biology, and economics.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 21:38:39 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://hiancemathbooks.com/relations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ordered Pairs</title>
      <link>http://hiancemathbooks.com/relations/ordered-pairs/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:22:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://hiancemathbooks.com/relations/ordered-pairs/index.html</guid>
      <description>Just as we saw how sets can be built via propositional logic, we’ll see how relations and functions are built up using sets, a clear example of how multiple seemingly disperate concepts can be accumulated into a cohesive whole. But before we delve into what relations and functions are exactly, there is one more set operation we should get acquainted with: the set product. Ironically, even though order doesn’t matter when considering elements in a set, constructing a set product does require that we know in what order we are doing things. In this section, we discuss a new type of mathematical object that takes order into account.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cartesian Products</title>
      <link>http://hiancemathbooks.com/relations/cartesian-products/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 15:21:45 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://hiancemathbooks.com/relations/cartesian-products/index.html</guid>
      <description>All of the set operations we’ve seen so far simply take some combination of elements from two given sets, and form a new conglomerate set. The same will be true of Cartesian Products.&#xA;Cartesian Products For all of the set operations we’ve seen so far, we essentially pick out only a subset of elements from each. What’s different about the Cartesian Product is that we iterate over all elements from both sets.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Properties of the Cartesian Product</title>
      <link>http://hiancemathbooks.com/relations/properties-of-the-cartesian-product/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:23:38 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://hiancemathbooks.com/relations/properties-of-the-cartesian-product/index.html</guid>
      <description>The Cartesian Product of two sets is just another set. This means we can also use other set operations like union, intersection, and set differences.&#xA;In this section, we explore how the Cartesian Product interacts with the other set operators.&#xA;Associativity of the Cartesian Product We already discussed how order matters in Cartesian Products, and as such sets don’t commute around the Cartesian Product operator $\times$. Associativity is another common property we should examine. What exactly is the difference between</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relations</title>
      <link>http://hiancemathbooks.com/relations/relations/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:24:08 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://hiancemathbooks.com/relations/relations/index.html</guid>
      <description>When we form the Cartesian Product $A \times B$, we are essentially pairing up every element in A with every element in B. However, we may not want to associate every element of A with every element in B. Instead, we may only want to pair up certain elements together because they satisfy some condition.&#xA;The way we pair up only certain elements from A to certain elements of B is to take a subset of $A \times B$. These kinds of subsets are yet another fundamental structure that appear all throughout all of mathematics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphical Representations of Relations</title>
      <link>http://hiancemathbooks.com/relations/graphical-representations-of-relations/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 21:38:39 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://hiancemathbooks.com/relations/graphical-representations-of-relations/index.html</guid>
      <description>As seen in the previous section, some relations involve nested structures. For example, some relations have elements that contain ordered pairs. Remember that all elements in a relation are ordered pairs themselves, meaning the elements of some relations are ordered pairs that also contain ordered pairs. As such, when we were listing out all of the elements of a relation, we sometimes spaced them out to make it easier to see what was in each of the elements. We saw this in Example 4.4.1, and Example 4.4.8.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>