<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Relations and Functions :: Maximum Mathematics</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/relations-and-functions/index.html</link>
    <description>Relations and functions are used all throughout mathematics. Examples of functions abound in subjects such as algebra, trigonometry, calculus, as well as computer science, physics, chemistry, biology, and economics.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 15:21:45 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/relations-and-functions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ordered Pairs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/relations-and-functions/ordered-pairs/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:22:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/relations-and-functions/ordered-pairs/index.html</guid>
      <description>Just as we saw how sets can be built via propositional logic, we’ll see how relations and functions are built up using sets, a clear example of how multiple seemingly disperate concepts can be accumulated into a cohesive whole. But before we delve into what relations and functions are exactly, there is one more set operation we should get acquainted with: the set product. Ironically, even though order doesn’t matter when considering elements in a set, constructing a set product does require that we know in what order we are doing things. In this section, we discuss a new type of mathematical object that takes order into account.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cartesian Products</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/relations-and-functions/cartesian-products/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 15:21:45 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/relations-and-functions/cartesian-products/index.html</guid>
      <description>All of the set operations we’ve seen so far simply take some combination of elements from two given sets, and form a new conglomerate set. The same will be true of Cartesian Products.&#xA;Cartesian Products For all of the set operations we’ve seen so far, we essentially pick out only a subset of elements from each. What’s different about the Cartesian Product is that we iterate over all elements from both sets.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Properties of the Cartesian Product</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/relations-and-functions/properties-of-the-cartesian-product/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:23:38 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/relations-and-functions/properties-of-the-cartesian-product/index.html</guid>
      <description>The Cartesian Product of two sets is just another set. This means we can also use other set operations like union, intersection, and set differences.&#xA;In this section, we explore how the Cartesian Product interacts with the other set operators.&#xA;Associativity of the Cartesian Product We already discussed how order matters in Cartesian Products, and as such sets don’t commute around the Cartesian Product operator $\times$. Associativity is another common property we should examine. What exactly is the difference between</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/relations-and-functions/relations/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:24:08 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/relations-and-functions/relations/index.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>